<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Jiri Eischmann -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.intoolswetrust.JSignPdf</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MPL-2.0 AND LGPL-2.1-only</project_license>
  <name>JSignPdf</name>
  <summary>Add digital signatures to PDF documents</summary>
  <developer id="io.github.intoolswetrust">
    <name>JSignPdf Project</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
    <p>JSignPdf is a free, open source application that adds digital signatures to PDF documents. It supports visible and hidden signatures, certificate levels, timestamping, and batch processing from the command line.</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Visible and hidden digital signatures</li>
      <li>Certificate levels and timestamping (TSA)</li>
      <li>PDF encryption and rights management</li>
      <li>Certificate revocation checks (CRL, OCSP)</li>
      <li>Command-line batch processing</li>
      <li>PKCS#11 hardware token support</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.intoolswetrust.JSignPdf.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://jsignpdf.eu/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/intoolswetrust/jsignpdf/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/intoolswetrust/jsignpdf</url>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#faa298</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#7f2c22</color>
  </branding>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="3.1.0" date="2026-07-13">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/intoolswetrust/jsignpdf/releases/tag/JSignPdf_3_1_0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Version 3.1.0</p>
        <p>Packaging-focused release: the fat jar is gone and every supported platform ships a native installer with its own bundled Java runtime. Also introduces a pluggable signing-engine architecture with a new EU DSS (PAdES) engine.</p>
        <ul>
          <li><em>Per-platform native installers</em> built with <code>jpackage</code> and a bundled Zulu+FX 21 runtime, so no system Java is required: Windows MSI, Linux DEB and RPM, and macOS DMG, each alongside a portable ZIP. Flatpak bundles are published for Linux x64 and aarch64.</li>
          <li><em>Two cross-platform ZIPs</em> for users who already have Java 21: a <code>full</code> ZIP carrying JavaFX natives for all platforms (with a Swing fallback when none match) and a <code>minimal</code> ZIP without JavaFX for headless/CLI signing and downstream packagers.</li>
          <li><em>Fat jar dropped</em> — the shaded all-in-one jar is no longer produced; the cross-platform ZIPs use <code>bin/jsignpdf.sh</code> and <code>bin\jsignpdf.cmd</code> launchers instead. The library jar published to Maven Central is unchanged.</li>
          <li><em>Pluggable signing engines</em> selectable with the new <code>--list-engines</code> and <code>-eng</code> / <code>--engine</code> options or the Engine selector in Preferences. JSignPdf ships <em>OpenPDF</em> as the default engine.</li>
          <li><em>New EU DSS (PAdES) engine</em> (id <code>dss</code>) producing PAdES signatures at the ETSI baseline levels B, T, LT, and LTA, which the OpenPDF engine cannot create.</li>
          <li><em>Default hash algorithm is now SHA-256</em> (was SHA-1) for signing that relies on the implicit default. An explicit or saved <code>hash.algorithm</code> is untouched, and SHA-1 stays selectable for the OpenPDF engine.</li>
          <li><em>CLI signatures now append by default</em>, matching the GUI. Use the new <code>--overwrite</code> flag to replace existing signatures; the legacy <code>--append</code> / <code>-a</code> flag is kept as a no-op.</li>
          <li><em>Signed Windows installers</em> — the Windows MSI installers are Authenticode-signed via SignPath, so they install without an unknown-publisher warning. Pre-release builds ship unsigned.</li>
          <li><em>Configurable default output suffix</em> — the <code>_signed</code> marker appended to the output file name can now be changed with the new <code>output.suffix</code> key in <code>advanced.properties</code>, so non-English users can localize it (e.g. <code>_firmado</code>). It feeds both GUIs and the default for the CLI <code>-os</code> / <code>--out-suffix</code> option.</li>
          <li><em>Checksums for every artifact</em> — a <code>jsignpdf-&lt;version&gt;-SHA256SUMS.txt</code> file now covers all published release assets.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.1" date="2026-05-07">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/intoolswetrust/jsignpdf/releases/tag/JSignPdf_3_0_1</url>
      <description>
        <p>Version 3.0.1</p>
        <p>Patch release fixing the Linux Flatpak build for the 3.0.0 release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix: drop the stale conf/ reference from the Flatpak manifests</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2026-05-07">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/intoolswetrust/jsignpdf/releases/tag/JSignPdf_3_0_0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Version 3.0.0</p>
        <p>Major release with a brand-new desktop UI and modernized packaging.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New JavaFX GUI with PDF preview, drag-to-place visible signatures, and drag-and-drop loading; legacy Swing UI remains available via -Djsignpdf.swing=true</li>
          <li>New Windows installers built with jpackage (EXE, MSI, portable ZIP with bundled JRE)</li>
          <li>New Linux Flatpak bundle with bundled OpenJDK 21</li>
          <li>Java 21 is now the minimum runtime</li>
          <li>Named signature-setting presets — save and switch between signing configurations</li>
          <li>Configuration moved to XDG-aware locations; legacy ~/.JSignPdf settings migrate automatically</li>
          <li>Read passwords from stdin (opt in with --enable-stdin-passwords)</li>
          <li>Migrated PDF engine to OpenPDF 3; updated PDFBox to 3.0.7 and BouncyCastle to 1.84</li>
          <li>Improved symlink handling on macOS; UTF-8 translation bundles with many language updates</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://jsignpdf.eu/img/screenshots/jsignpdf-javafx-main.png</image>
      <caption>JSignPdf main window</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://jsignpdf.eu/img/screenshots/jsignpdf-javafx-signed.png</image>
      <caption>JSignPdf - signing completed</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://jsignpdf.eu/img/screenshots/jsignpdf-javafx-visible-sig.png</image>
      <caption>JSignPdf - placing visible signature</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
</component>
